圣何塞圣文德医院
好消息  有位贵宾病患需要在手肘
Good news. I have a VIP who needs a multiple ligament
做多处韧带重建术
reconstruction on his elbow,
我有两个协助我和梅伦德斯医生的住院医名额
and I've got room for a couple residents to assist me and Dr. Melendez.
太棒了
Awesome.
我之前从没协助过这种手术
I've never assisted on one of those before.
安德鲁斯医生清楚
Dr. Andrews knows that.
所以他才用圣诞节清晨的语气宣布消息
That's why he's acting like it's Christmas morning.
我猜你也没给职业运动员做过手术
I'm guessing you've never operated on a pro athlete, either.
据我所知
Um, last time I checked,
你说的是两个名额  但我们有三人
a "Couple" means "Two," and there's three of us.
还有个好消息
More good news.
剩下那名住院医师将协助科利医生
Whoever isn't with us will be assisting Dr. Coyle
做双腿筋膜切开术
on a double-leg fasciotomy.
试试手气
Feeling lucky?
莫菲
Murphy.
贵宾手肘  棒
VIP elbow. Sweet.
筋膜切开术
Fasciotomy.
博比·奥托  我好像没听说过
Bobby Ato? Don't think I've heard of him.
他是职业运动员吗
He's a pro athlete?
是职业的  但不知道算不算运动员
He's a pro. I don't know if I'd call him in athlete.
电子运动
E-sports.
电子游戏吗
Video games?
他是世上首屈一指的玩家
He's one of the best in the world.
去年他获得的奖金
Last year, he won enough prize money
都够给他妈妈在蒙特雷买幢沙滩别墅了
to buy his mom a beach house in Monterey.
还是现金支付
Paid cash.
他被列为贵宾病患
Is he considered a very important person
是因为他是运动员还是因为他很有钱
because he's an athlete or because he has a lot of money?
-都是  -都是
- Both. - Both.
我得走了
I have to go.
早上好  肖恩
Morning, Shaun.
这位是梅丽莎·伯恩
This is Melissa Bourne,
我跟你提过的那位治疗师
the therapist that we talked about.
你答应和她见面了的  肖恩
That you agreed to meet with, right, Shaun?
你好  肖恩  很高兴见到你
Hi, Shaun. It's nice to meet you.
你好
H-H-Hi.
格拉斯曼医生觉得在第一次上门治疗前
Dr. Glassman thought it would be a good idea for us to meet
我们最好见一面
before our first in-home session.
好让你感到自在些
Just to make sure you're comfortable.
我不自在
I am not comfortable.
肖恩
Shaun.
没事的
It's gonna be fine.
你们会喜欢彼此的
You two are going to like each other.
伯恩医生是认知心理学的博士
Dr. Bourne has a PhD in cognitive psychology.
她真的能帮到你  只要你给她个机会
She can really help you, but you have to give her a chance.
好吗
Okay?
好  好
'Kay. Okay.
我为你骄傲  肖恩
I'm proud of you, Shaun.
我已经为你感到骄傲了
I'm already proud of you.
良     医
第一季    第十集
注意零度分离
Notice the separation at zero degrees.
显示外侧副韧带和尺侧副韧带完全撕裂
It's indicative of complete tears of the LCL and the UCL.
完全应该动手术
A perfect candidate for surgery.
你妈妈怎么样  还在抗癌吗
How's your mom? Still beating cancer?
她很好  哥们儿
She's good, bro.
她说自从你给她做了乳房重建后
She said she gets checked out at the beach all the time
她在沙滩上总能收获很多目光
ever since you did her breast reconstruction.
所以谢谢你咯
So, uh, thanks. I guess.
我们会治好你的
We're gonna take good care of you.
-手术室见  -谢谢
- See you in the O.R. - Thank you.
尺侧副韧带哪一部分是过度外翻动作的
Which part of the UCL is the principal secondary
主要辅助约束
to excessive valgus movement?
-前部  -还好吗
- Anterior. - Everything okay?
我没事
Yes, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
捏捏我的手
Squeeze my hands.
外上髁  肌腱  内部
左手存在反常的握力缺失现象
There is a paradoxical loss of grip strength on the left.
有很多可能的原因
There are many possible explanations for that,
-其中之一...  -其中之一是...
- one of which I-- - One of which is...
他的左臂韧带撕裂
he has ligament tears in his left arm.
麻醉师很快就来
The anesthesiologist will be up in a few
帮你做术前准备
to get you ready for surgery.
好极了  谢谢
Dope. Thank you.
莫菲医生
Dr. Murphy.
-你怎么了  -没事
- What's wrong with you? - N-nothing.
我的情况是...
I have a condition called --
你有自闭症  对对  我知道
You're autistic. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Mm, I get it.
但你到底怎么了  哥们儿
But what is wrong with you, bro?
你该像个外科医生那样大显身手
You gotta be legit smart to land a gig as a surgeon
却被他像对待菜鸟医生一样否定了
and he just shut you down like a noob.
我会再次提出我的想法  我会的
I'll bring the idea up again. I do that.
他们不尊重你
They don't respect you.
他们一开始就该听你说完
And they should listen to you the first time.
-我没法控制他们的行为  -你当然能
- I can't control what they do. - Of course you can.
这就是打游戏的关键
That's what playing the game is all about.
就在于控制敌方
It's about controlling your opponent.
你得找到合适的策略
You gotta find the right strategy.
这不是游戏
It is not a game.
一切都是游戏  兄弟  一切都是游戏
Everything's a game, man. Everything's a game.
只是有时赌注要大一些
Just sometimes the stakes are higher,
而这次的赌注是我的手臂
and this time it's my arm.
看来是你抽到了下下签
So, I'm guessing you drew the short straw.
-你说什么  -你在这
- I beg your pardon? - Well, you're here
而你的住院医师同事们在跟进贵宾病例
and your co-residents are on the VIP case.
我很厉害  但我还是更想跟梅伦德斯和安德鲁斯
I'm awesome and I'd still rather be with Melendez and Andrews.
-不  没事  -别激动  没事的
- No, it's fine -- - Relax. It's cool.
跟我说说病患情况
Tell me about our patient.
34岁  女性  软件工程师  企业家
Uh, 34-year-old female, software engineer and entrepreneur
在单车课上因用力过猛导致了骨筋膜室综合征
presenting with Compartment Syndrome caused by extreme overexertion at a spin class.
导致她的腿部肌肉...
The condition has caused the muscles in her legs to --
-很好  -我还没说完
- Okay. Great. - I wasn't finished.
足够体现你的聪明和仔细了
Finished enough to show me you're smart and thorough.
知道治疗方案了吗
You know the treatment plan?
-需要切口...  -很好
- We need to make incisions on -- - Good.
你带头
You take lead.
我们要在每条腿的两侧
We need to make a number of long incisions
切开几处切口以缓解压力
down both sides of each leg to relieve the tension
并恢复正常血液循环
and return healthy circulation.
重要的是得赶紧手术
It's important we act quickly.
如果没控制住肿胀
If we don't get the swelling under control,
损伤将无法挽回
the damage could be irreparable.
什么意思  我需要截肢吗
What does that mean? I could lose my legs?
就因为单车课上用力过猛了
From working out too hard in a spin class?
别担心  你姐姐不会有事的
No, don't worry. Your sister's gonna be just fine.
我很确信发现得很及时
Look, I'm very confident we caught this in time.
麻烦向前趴一下
If you could lean forward?
我得检查你的肾脏没受影响
I just need to check your kidneys haven't been affected.
如果有触痛请告诉我
Let me know if you have any tenderness.
现在取出掌肌
Extracting the palmaris now.
安德鲁斯医生  我看了你在《激流新闻》的评论
Dr. Andrews, I read your op-ed in Gen Surge News.
文章很出色
Brilliant piece.
从没想到持续护理不足
Never realized the lack of continuity of care
是如此严重的问题
was such a severe problem.
梅伦德斯医生
Dr. Melendez...
你的头发很漂亮
you have very beautiful hair.
谢谢
Thank you.
鉴于病患的握力缺失情况
Given the patient's grip weakness,
我们可以做一个神经传导实验
we could do a nerve conduction test
以排除任何并发的神经损害
to rule out any concurrent nerve damage.
不行
No.
好了  似乎现在可以暂停一下
Okay, that looks like a good stopping point.
卡卢医生  你来
Dr. Kalu...step in.
-有什么问题吗  -没有  看起来很好
- Something wrong? -No, it looks good.
我只是想给卡卢医生一个机会
I just want to give Dr. Kalu an opportunity
让他展示一下他的能耐
to show us what he can do.
只要你没意见就行
As long as that's okay with you.
当然
Sure.
谢谢  安德鲁斯医生
Thank you, Dr. Andrews.
好了  看上去不错
All right, looking good.
开始做另一侧
Let's move to the lateral side.
姑娘们  今晚我们去哪儿玩
So, what are we doing tonight, ladies?
去非凡酒吧怎么样
How about we go to Viva's?
好主意
Sounds good.
电刀
Bovie.
你怎么这么安静  布朗医生
You're awfully quiet over there, Dr. Browne.
我只是在专注做事
I'm just focused.
我知道你平时都和梅伦德斯一起上手术
I know you're used to operating with Melendez,
但我们这比较有意思
but we have fun here.
我觉得当人们放松时
I feel like when it's less tense,
会更少犯错
people make fewer mistakes.
好的
Okay.
你想做另一条腿吗
You wanna take the other leg?
真的
Really?
当然  实践是最好的学习方式  不是吗
Yeah, best way to learn is by doing it, right?
当然
Definitely.
那就放手去做吧
So go for it.
BGM: Ordinary Man by Eels
? Well, it's another warm day ?
? In the city of cold hearts ?
《神经外科临床指南》
? They all just play the part of who they are ?
? And I'm here on my own ?
? I'd rather be alone ?
梅利莎在你家等你呢
你去哪了
? Than try to be someone that I'm not ?
删除信息
取消  确定
? And you seem like someone who could appreciate the fact ?
? That I'm no ordinary man ?
肖恩  早上好
Shaun, good morning.
早上好  格拉斯曼医生
Good morning, Dr. Glassman.
和梅利莎聊得怎么样
How'd it go with Melissa?
她对我...
She was...
帮助很大
very helpful.
你穿的衣服和昨天一样  肖恩
You're wearing the same clothes as yesterday, Shaun.
你先请
After you.
很显然我们各执己见
Apparently we are at an impasse.
我真的认为梅利莎可以帮到你
I feel strongly that Melissa can be very helpful to you.
而你却完全不这么认为
You feel so strongly that she can't
甚至愿意为此牺牲良好的睡眠和个人卫生
that you're willing to sacrifice a good night's sleep and hygiene.
肖恩  你身上有味道了
Shaun, you smell.
我会在医生休息室冲个澡
I will shower in the doctor's lounge.
那真是太好了
Well, great.
至少一个问题解决了
That solves one problem.
你不惜待在这一整晚  就为了逃避面谈
You stayed here all night just to avoid a confrontation.
直接说「不去」就好  肖恩
Just say "No," Shaun.
直接说「不去」
You know? Just say "No."
不去
No!
No.
很好  好极了
Great. That's just great.
我不用非得去见梅利莎
I don't have to see Melissa?
不用  你不用非得去见梅利莎
No, you don't have to see Melissa.
你是个成年人了  你可以自己拿主意
You're a grown man. You can make your own decisions.
我只是觉得她会对你有所帮助
I just happen to feel that she could be of great help to you.
这...
That...
这样吧
I'll tell you what.
如果你见三次梅利莎
You see Melissa three times
我就给你买你想要装在电视上的环绕声系统如何
and I will buy you the surround-sound system you want for your television.
你在收买我吗
Are you bribing me?
我想是的
I suppose I am.
如果你不喜欢她  她会离开
If you don't like her, she'll leave.
而且我保证我之后再也不会插手这件事
And I promise I will never say another word about it.
这是个很棒的交易
That's a pretty good deal.
好吧
Okay.
好
我今晚会和她见面
I will meet with her tonight.
这就对了  肖恩
That's good, Shaun.
生理盐水吗  我之前从未见过这种方法
Saline? I've never seen it done quite like that.
我有个教授来自葡萄牙
Yeah, I had a professor from Portugal.
他们那里就是这么做的
Apparently it's how they do it over there.
这可以缓解疼痛
It's supposed to lessen the pain.
好消息是你的组织活性良好  呈粉红色
Well, the good news is your tissue is nice and pink,
这说明你的腿很健康
which means it's healthy.
不幸的是  水肿并没有如我们所愿的消下去
Unfortunately, the swelling is not coming down like we'd hoped.
这是不是意味着你们要给我截肢了
Does this mean you're going to have to amputate?
不  不  有时我们需要时间
No, no. Sometimes it just takes time.
我们会治好你的
We'll take care of you.
做得很好  布朗医生
Very nice work, Dr. Browne.
能帮我个忙  交换一下患者吗
Can you do me a solid and trade patients?
不  不可能  安德鲁斯让我主管患者
No, not a chance. Andrews let me take lead.
科利也让我主管
Coyle let me take lead, too.
那有什么问题
So what is the problem?
他有点太过友好了
He's a little too friendly.
他很奇怪地拍了我的背
He patted my back in a weird way.
我说不好  我觉得有些尴尬
I don't know. It was -- It was awkward.
我想他只是想和你融洽相处而已
I'm sure he's just trying to establish a rapport.
或许吧
Maybe?
我不知...
I don't...
肖恩  换吗
Shaun? Switch?
不换
No.
我喜欢博比
I like Bobby.
他可以给我很好的建议
He has very good advice.
所以  谁都做了什么
So, who did what?
大部分手术是由我和安德鲁斯医生完成的
Well, I did, uh, most of the surgery along with Dr. Andrews
卡卢医生负责更换你的一条撕裂韧带
and Dr. Kalu aided in replacing one of your torn ligaments.
几周之内你就能恢复到竞技状态
You should be back in competition shape in a few weeks time.
酷毙了
Word.
那你呢  你做了什么
What about you? What'd you do?
我帮忙清理植入的肌腱
I helped to clean the grafted tendons.
就这样
That's it.
是的
Yes.
拜托  你没有在这里面鼓捣鼓捣吗
Come on. You didn't get up in there?
你的肌无力症状
Y-Your muscle weakness
伴随体温升高
along with the high body temperature
很可能是多发性硬化的早期症状
could be an early indicator of multiple sclerosis.
我们应该预约磁共振检查
We should order an MRI.
我们已经讨论过无数次了
We have talked about this countless times.
是的  我们应该预约磁共振检查
Yes. We should order an MRI.
我们不会预约磁共振检查的
We are not ordering an MRI.
你不尊重我
You don't respect me.
现在确实不怎么尊重
Not right now, I don't.
安德鲁斯医生  梅伦德斯医生
Dr. Andrews, Dr. Melendez.
我们现在正和职业运动员打交道
Given the fact we're dealing with a pro athlete,
就算是打个小嗝都应该慎重对待
even the slightest hiccup could be problematic.
我想博比会欣赏我们的用心
I think Bobby would be impressed by our being extra attentive.
卡卢说得对
Kalu is right.
现在正是他作为专业运动员的鼎盛时期
he is a pro athlete in his prime earning years.
我们应该百分之百确保他没事
We should make sure we leave him 100%.
去做磁共振
Do the MRI.
干得漂亮  你说服他们了
Nice score. You got 'em to listen.
去做磁共振
Do the MRI.
不是我  是杰瑞德说服他们了
No, Jared did.
为什么他能做到  而你不行
How did he get there when you couldn't?
他说得很友好
He asked nicely.
你说得也很友好
Okay, you asked nicely.
是的  没错
Yes. Yes, I did.
你要是想要荣耀  就得激烈些  哥们
You gotta be fierce if you want the glory, bro.
不
Oh, no.
我不想要荣耀  哥们
I do not want the glory, bro.
我只想成为一个好的外科医生
I just want to be a good surgeon.
谁都想要荣耀
Everyone wants glory.
人们因此而实现欲望
It -- It's how you get what you want.
每个人都有欲望
And everybody's got wants.
我想要环绕声扬声器系统
I want a surround-sound speaker system.
我需要去见治疗师才能得到它
To get it, I have to see a therapist.
我不想要去见治疗师
I don't want to have to see a therapist.
好吧  我就是那么得到第一台PS2游戏机的
Okay, yeah, that's -- that's how I got my first PS2.
我父母分开之后  收买我去见的治疗师
Yeah, my parents bribed me to go to therapy after they split up.
治疗师什么样
What was therapy like?
挺简单的  哥们
Pretty basic, bro.
她告诉我该做什么
She'd tell me what to do,
如何与我父母相处
how to deal with my parents.
有帮助吗
Was it helpful?
我说不好
I don't know.
我从没做过任何她让我做的事
I never did anything she told me to do.
可以这样吗
Is that an option?
跟从自己的心  永远没问题
Doing whatever the hell you feel like doing is always an option.
我就提醒一下
Just a gentle reminder --
今晚八点和我爸吃饭
dinner with my dad tonight at 8:00.
我记在日程表中了
It is on my calendar.
吉普赛国王演唱会也记在日程表中了
So was the Gypsy Kings concert,
但我记得...
and I -- I seem to remember...
有道理
Fair enough.
贵宾病例如何了
How is the VIP case?
肖恩似乎有些不对劲
Shaun seems off about something.
你和他谈过了吗
Did you talk to him?
是啊  和肖恩谈话就能解决问题
Yes. Because talking to Shaun solves problems.
而安德鲁斯...
And Andrews is...
他是你的眼中钉
He's a pain in your ass.
不  实际上他太过友好了
No. He's actually too friendly.
杰瑞德拍了他的马屁  他就突然不再刻薄了
Jared kisses his ass and suddenly he's cutting.
拍马屁是外科医生的实用技能
Well, ass kissing is a useful skill for a surgeon.
你的衬衫真好看
That's a very beautiful blouse.
我还得去吃晚餐吗
Do I still have to go to dinner?
是的  会很好的
Yes. It'll be nice.
你会喝点好红酒  我爸会付账
You'll have some nice wine and my dad will pay.
他会逼我们定下婚礼日期的
He'll push us to set a wedding date.
4月25号
April 25th.
你预定什么了吗
Did you book something?
没有
No.
但我爸不需要知道这些
But my dad doesn't need to know that.
有什么消息
What do you got?
手术修复手肘看起来没问题
Looks like the surgically repaired elbow is fine.
如我所料
As I suspected.
但莫菲注意到了周边的问题
But Murphy noticed something in the periphery,
高一点的地方  就在二头肌上方
a little higher up, just above the bicep.
是我的主意
It was my idea.
是的  我刚刚说了
Yes, I just said that.
所以我们拍了高些地方的片  并注意到了这个
So, we took an image from higher up and noticed this.
完全包括住了他的臂丛神经
It's encasing the entirety of his brachial plexus.
这太大了
This thing is massive.
活检明确显示这是神经鞘瘤
Biopsy indicated it's definitely a schwannoma.
并且明显是恶性的
And it's definitely malignant.
这地方很棘手  但也许你能移除
It's in a tricky spot, but you might be able to remove it.
根据放疗化疗结合的手法...
Follow it up with a combo of radiotherapy and chemo to finish it o...
怎么了  有什么问题
What? What's the problem?
博比·奥托  博比·奥托  职业玩家博比·奥托
Robert Ato. Bobby Ato. Pro-gamer Bobby Ato?
你是他的粉丝吗
You a fan?
我三年前遇到过他
I met him three years ago.
我在旧金山市立医院当肿瘤学顾问
Oncology consult for SF Muni.
他三年前得过癌症
He had cancer three years ago?
你为什么没告诉我们你得过癌症
Why the hell wouldn't you tell us that you had already had cancer?
那是三年前  在我的小腿部位
It was in my lower leg three years ago.
那和你如何治疗我的手肘有什么关系
How's that gonna change how you fix my elbow?
这对我如何看待莫菲医生提到的症状影响巨大
It would have a huge effect on how I viewed the symptoms that Dr. Murphy noticed.
你没听莫菲医生的话
You didn't listen to Dr. Murphy
因为你不尊重他
because you don't respect him.
因为莫菲医生和常人不同
'Cause Dr. Murphy is different.
我尊重他
I respect him.
他有好想法  也有坏想法
He has good ideas, and he has bad ideas.
看来你否定的这个是个好想法
Turns out this was a good one. That you shot down.
你为什么隐瞒真相
Why did you hide the truth?
之前的肿瘤诊断并不丢人
A previous cancer diagnosis isn't shameful.
首诊之后  我脑袋里全部都是
After the first diagnosis, all I was thinking was,
「还会回来吗  有多糟糕呢」
"Will it come back? How bad will it be?"
我心烦意乱  哥们
I was distracted, man.
我没法专心  我接连失败
I couldn't focus, and I hit a slump --
你担心癌症扰乱了你的比赛
Wait, you were worried that cancer was messing with your gaming?
没错  哥们
Yeah, man!
癌症让我与冠军失之交臂
It cost me a championship.
我决定将之与所有负面情绪和身体的虚弱
I decided to block it out along with all the thoughts
一起拒之门外
of negativity and physical weakness,
并由此成为了世界第一
and like that, I became the best in the world.
我们需要做全身扫描
We need to do a full-body scan
确保癌症没有转移
to make sure the cancer has not already metastasized.
他说了
What he said.
我说的
What I said.
看起来不错
This looks great.
肿胀开始消退了
The swelling is starting to reduce.
我们可以开始缩紧缝合了
We can start tightening the sutures.
终于有好消息了
Finally some good news.
你看起来也好多了
You look like you're doing better, too...
你上司不在之后
now your boss is gone.
科利医生吗  他挺好的
Dr. Coyle? He's fine.
和我你不用「紧跟党的路线」
You don't have to toe the party line with me.
相信我  我明白
Trust me. I get it.
我差点在单车课上骑车而死
I almost rode myself to death in a spin class
就因为我听见几个投资者说
because I overheard a couple of investors say
他们「觉得我的观念还行」
that they "liked the concept just fine,"
但我的脚踝「太让人分心」了
but that my cankles were "too distracting."
什么  你的想法非常棒
What? Your idea is brilliant.
而且你很美  去他们的
And you're beautiful. Screw those jackasses.
格蕾丝  你不明白
Grace, you don't get it.
你的脸很美  腰臀比正好
You got the face, perfect little hip-to-waist ratio,
大部分投资公司都是一群男人经营的
and most VC firms are run by a bunch of bros,
所以我臀部的大小和我能筹集到的钱财之间
so there is an inverse relationship between the size of my ass
有着反比关系
and how much money I can raise.
那你应该做些别的
Then you should do something else
避免和这群男人打交道
where you don't have to deal with bros.
做什么  修女吗
Like what, become a nun?
-抱歉  -你同意她的话
- Sorry. - You agree with her?
她差点害死自己
She nearly worked herself to death
就为了取悦几头有钱的猪猡
trying to please some pigs with money?
她不该如此
She shouldn't have to.
好极了  你要是找到了乌托邦  一定要告诉我
Great. Let me know when you find utopia.
但在那之前  我热爱我的工作
But until then, I love what I do.
所以我得遵守游戏规则  因为我要是让他们滚
So I got to play the game 'cause if I call them out,
我只会被贴上「婊子」的标签  甚至更糟
I just get labeled a "Bitch," or even worse.
你的心率升高了
Your heart rate's going up.
黑兹尔
Hazel?
她快无法呼吸了
She's barely moving any air.
黑兹尔  能听到我说话吗
Hazel, can you hear me?
紧急呼叫  我得给她插管
Code blue! I need to intubate her.
给我一个咽喉镜和气管内管
Give me a laryngoscope and an ET tube.
给她吸纯氧
Let's get her on 100% oxygen.
紧急呼叫  四楼北面  407房间
Code blue. 4 North, room 407.
说说情况
Talk to me.
她的肺
Her lungs --
我认为再灌注损伤了
I think it's a reperfusion injury.
里面没有空间了
There's no room in here.
气道情况三级  甚至四级  你应该接手
Mallampati 3, maybe 4. You should take over.
你做得很好  给  用探条
You're doing fine. Here, use the bougie.
-感觉到会厌软骨了吗  -好像有
- You feel the epiglottis? - I think so.
好  再进去一点  你应该感觉进不去了
Okay, go a bit further, you should feel it stop.
如果能继续进去  那你就到了食道
If it keeps going, you're in the esophagus.
进不去了  好了  气管内管
It stopped, got it. ET tube?
会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
干得漂亮  医生
Strong work, Doctor.
不管是不是世界第一  这家伙疯了
Best in the world or not, this guy's insane.
竟然想躲过诊断
Hiding from a diagnosis?
没用的  它会找上你
Doesn't work -- it'll find you.
博比想成为最棒的  他是最棒的
Bobby wanted to be the best. He is the best.
我觉得他不是想成为最棒的
I don't think he was trying to be the best.
他应该只是害怕了
I think he was just scared.
那是什么  脑干旁边的
What's that? Next to the brain stem.
另一个神经鞘瘤
Another schwannoma.
正面情绪的力量到此为止
So much for the power of positive thinking.
这孩子真奇怪  他得过癌症
He's a strange kid. He had cancer.
就因为有所失去而停止跟进疾病
Stopped going to follow-ups because he started losing.
哪里奇怪了
What's so strange?
听着就是典型的否认情绪
Sounds like a classic case of denial.
我在想我们是否可以尝试新方法
I was thinking we could try something new.
或许用伽马刀
Maybe gamma knife?
我觉得不行  不适用于这种肿瘤
I don't think so. Wrong type of tumor for that.
如果我每过几个月就告诉你
What if I told you every few months
你很有可能要死  你会怎么样
that you had a real possibility you were gonna die?
我会很害怕  而且会听医生的话
I'd be scared. And I'd listen.
你可能会  也可能不会
Maybe you would, maybe you wouldn't.
就我个人而言  我觉得他没错
Personally, I think he's right --
拒绝这些世界末日的声音
shut down those voices of doom,
把时间用来去生活而不是等待死亡
spend your days living instead of dying.
但他也可能疯了
But he may also be crazy.
除了把他变成植物人
Short of making him a vegetable,
我不知道我们还能做什么
I don't know if there's anything we can do.
肖恩还好吗
Is -- Is Shaun okay?
他的工作还好吗
Is his work okay?
都好  只是
Yes, I just, um --
那他就没事
Then he's fine.
该死
Damn.
马进到酒吧来了
Horse walks into a bar.
酒保说...
Bartender says...
我们发现了另一处肿瘤
We found another mass.
虽然事与愿违  但没事
That's not how it goes, but cool.
我们也把它取出来
Let's knock it out, too.
肿瘤长在你的脑干上
The mass is located on your brain stem.
脑干是控制你的自主神经系统
Which controls your autonomic nervous system --
你的心脏和呼吸的
your heart, respiration.
其所在的位置让我们无法进行手术
Its positioning makes it inoperable.
我有过好成绩
I...had a good run.
我希望能持续更久  但...
Wish it was longer, but...
我在巅峰时刻结束
I'm gonna go out on top.
如果你们今天离开这个世界
If you went out today,
你们能说一样的话吗
could you say the same thing?
你当时在场是她的福气
She's lucky you were there.
我  你才是那个救了她的人
Me? You're the one who saved her.
在你的帮助下  很大的帮助
With your help. A lot of it.
所以  谢谢你
So, thank you.
你想喝一杯吗
Hey, look, you wanna -- you wanna get a drink?
也许缓一缓
Maybe take the edge off?
不用了  但还是谢谢你
No. But thank you, though.
你确定吗  我保证你会很开心
Are you sure? I promise you'll have fun.
我按摩手法很棒
I give great massages.
早上我会给你做一个好吃到死的煎蛋卷
And I'll make a killer omelet in the morning.
这真是太不合适了
That's really inappropriate.
我说了不
I said no.
抱歉  这又是哪一出
I'm sorry. W-W-- Where's this coming from?
你给了我很明确的暗示
You were -- You were clearly giving me signals.
不  我给你唯一的「暗示」
No, the only "Signal" I gave you
就是我对你完全不感兴趣
was that I wasn't interested in the slightest.
我只是听到你和卡卢
Okay, see, I just -- I heard about you and Kalu
在检录处约炮  所以我以为...
banging in the call room, so I figured --
谈话到此结束  你这个混蛋
This conversation is over. You're an ass.
我是个很随和的人
I'm pretty easygoing,
但你在违抗命令
but you're approaching insubordination.
你要举报我吗
You're gonna report me?
我不会举报任何人
I'm not gonna report anybody.
但也许下一次
But maybe next time,
当有人约你的时候  别这么死板
try not to have such a stick up your ass about being asked out.
拜托
Come on.
我一直以为小兔是最可爱的昵称
I always thought Bunny was the cutest nickname.
你当然这样认为  但当我12岁或20岁时
Of course you did, but you could've stopped calling me that
你可以不要那样叫我了
when I was 12 or -- or 20.
今天过得不顺吗
Rough day?
是的  发生了一些事
Yeah. Yeah, it was something.
这应该能让你开心点
Well, this should make you a little happier.
我决定承包你们整个婚礼
I have decided to take care of your entire wedding.
我们不需要
We don't need it.
不用谢
You're welcome.
我们又不是21岁的小孩
We're not 21.
我们能够轻松负担自己的婚礼
We're more than capable of paying for our own wedding.
我们赚的钱够多
We make good money.
但一旦你们有了孩子就不够了  小兔
But you won't once you start having kids, Bunny.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing in here?
我在躲避我的治疗师
I'm hiding from my therapist.
我得不到立体音响系统
I am not going to get a surround-sound speaker system.
但我会做任何我想做的事情
But I am doing whatever the hell I feel like doing.
可以把拖把递给我吗
Can you hand me that mop?
好的
Okay.
你对你的一生所做之事满意吗
Are you satisfied with what you've done with your life?
如果你明天就死了  你会开心吗
Would you be happy if you died tomorrow?
满意
Satisfied?
开心
Happy?
我在楼里做保洁...
I mean, I clean up a building, uh...
但我娶了此生挚爱
But I -- I married the love of my life.
我们养育了三个漂亮的孩子
Uh, we raised three beautiful kids.
其中一个有点淘气  但她现在乖多了
One of them had some troubles, but she's doing great now.
另外两个都做得很好
The other two are doing all right for themselves.
我对人也很友善
And I was good to people.
至少我这样认为
At least I think I was.
这个答案很棒
That's a very good answer.
如果你想看  我有女儿们的照片
I got pictures of the girls if you want see --
不用了
No.
你为什么要我辞职去组建家庭
So, why do I need to quit my job to have a family?
同意
Agreed.
她可以既是优秀的律师又是优秀的母亲
She can be a great lawyer and a great mom.
是的  她可以  但是为什么呢
Yes, she can, but why?
为什么要把时间浪费在工作上
W-Why waste your time working?
你应该像我一样  享受生活
You should be enjoying life, like me.
家庭信托里有很多钱
There's plenty in the family trust.
爸爸  我的工作很重要  我帮助人们
Dad, my work is important. I'm helping people --
小兔  你坐办公室
Bunny... you're pushing papers.
怎么能真的帮到人
How -- How is that really helping anyone?
也许我守旧  但我不明白
And maybe I'm old-fashioned, but I don't get it.
我以为你会更聪明
I-I thought you were smarter than that.
你宁愿她做懒惰的寄生虫
You'd prefer her to be a lazy parasite
靠信托基金过日子
living off a trust fund
而不是真的去为社会做贡献
as opposed to actually contributing to society?
寄生虫
Parasite?
我父亲赚了很多钱
My father made a lot of money.
我不会为此道歉
I'm not going to apologize for that.
他确保他的儿女和孙辈可以享受生活
He made sure his children and his grandchildren could enjoy their lives.
我没有伤害任何人
I'm not hurting anyone.
事实上  我用自己的方式帮助他人
In fact, I go out of my way to help people.
所以如果你认为我不值得尊敬  那么抱歉
So I'm sorry if that doesn't qualify me as a worthwhile person in your book.
我出去时会结账
I'll get the check on my way out.
爸爸  你不必...
Dad, you don't have to...
我做错了什么  肖恩
What am I doing wrong, Shaun?
我不知道
I don't know.
我试着...
I tried...
鼓励你  我试着支持你
encouraging, I've tried being supportive,
我试着讨好你
I've tried bribing you.
我不需要治疗师  不
I don't need a therapist. No.
看看四周  你看你睡在...
Look around you. What -- You're sleeping --
这个杂物室里
What is this, a broom closet?
看看你愿意做出的牺牲
Look at the sacrifices you're willing to make
只为了避开...
just to avoid...
我们稍后再聊
We're gonna pick this up later.
你得跟人事部提出投诉
You have to file a complaint with HR.
那样我会得到「敌意」和「难相处」的标签
I do that and I get labeled "Hostile" and "Difficult,"
对我的肤色和性别都没帮助
neither of which work with my complexion or gender.
正因此才更应该表态
All the more reason to take a stand.
克莱尔  这种情况就该找人事部
Claire, this situation is exactly what HR is for.
我没说这很容易
I didn't say it was easy.
是  你说了
Yeah, you did.
这挺可怕而且需要勇气
Look, it's scary and it takes courage,
但这是对的事
but it's the right thing to do.
这是无意义的事
It's a pointless thing to do.
-他们会听你说  -他们会把错怪在我身上
- They'll listen to you. - They will shift the blame onto me.
就像你一样
Like you did.
什么  我怎么...
Whoa, what? How did I --
我找你说
I came to you,
你指责我把情况夸大
you accused me of exaggerating to get back onto the case.
不不  我不是那个意思  我不知道...
No, no, no, that's not what I meant. I had no idea --
我说他太友好亲切了
I said he was too friendly.
你说他只是「试着建立密切关系」
You said he was "Trying to establish a rapport."
我是你的枕边人  杰瑞德
I'm sleeping with you, Jared,
而你都认为我反应过度了
and you thought I was overreacting.
你觉得三个陌生人会怎么看呢
How do you think three strangers will see things?
克莱尔  我很抱歉  非常抱歉
Claire, I'm sorry. I am so sorry.
别担心  那很正常
Don't worry about it. It's just the way it is.
我还有患者要去巡视
I've got a patient to round on.
我和梅伦德斯医生谈过了
Dr. Melendez and I had a talk
我们相信我们能切除肿瘤
and we believe we can excise the tumor
只要你愿意做出牺牲
if you're willing to make a sacrifice.
牺牲
Sacrifice?
听起来比死亡好
That sounds better than death.
我也是那么想
My thinking as well.
我们相信我们可以移除肿块
We believe we can remove the mass,
但我们也要从你的脑干取出一块东西
but we'll also have to take a piece out of your brain stem.
一块红核
A chunk of the red nucleus,
它的功能是控制你的左侧身体
which helps control the left side of your body.
你的那一侧会瘫痪
You'll be paralyzed on that side.
也可能造成进食和吞咽困难
It could also result in difficulty eating and swallowing.
说话困难
Speech difficulties.
我们做吧
Let's do it.
好样的
Good for you.
慢着  慢着
Hold on. Hold on.
博比  这手术风险很高
Bobby, this is very risky surgery.
你可能会死在手术台  就算一切顺利
You could die on the table, and even if all goes well,
你也会严重残疾
you will be severely disabled.
是的  我听到了  我接受
Yeah, I -- I was listening, and I'm in.
各位  我明白
Guys, hey, I get it.
如果我死了  我就死了
If I'm dead, I'm -- I'm dead.
如果没有  体育锻炼  再学习等等
But if not -- PT, relearning stuff, whatever.
都不会阻止我继续比赛
It's not gonna stop me from competing.
永远不会
Not ever.
博比  你的事业结束了
Bobby, your career is over.
你得明白这点
We need you to understand that.
是吗
Yeah?
一朝玩家  永世玩家
Once a gamer, always a gamer, huh?
我很钦佩你
You got my respect.
你发什么疯
What the hell is your problem?
如果你敢威胁克莱尔
If you ever threaten Claire,
跟她说话轻佻
take a disrespectful tone,
或是再敢斜视她
or so much as look at her cross-eyed again,
我会做出比把你推到墙上更可怕的事
I'm gonna do a hell of a lot more than put you up against a wall.
明白吗
We clear?
你的肺部情况好多了
Your lungs are looking a lot better.
总得来说你的情况不错
Overall, you're in pretty good shape.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
都是医生该做的
All part of the service.
你干得很好
And good for you.
我没睡着
I wasn't sleeping.
我听到你是怎么对付另一位医生的
I heard the way you handled that other doctor.
你全都听到了
You heard that? All of it?
但愿我也做得出来
I wish I had done that.
你很勇敢
You were brave.
不不
No, no.
我要是勇敢
If I was brave, I --
里克·艾伦
Rick Allen.
英国重金属新浪潮的代表性乐队之一
-谁  -威豹乐队的独臂鼓手
- Who? - One-armed drummer for Def Leppard.
拜托
Come on, man.
而这是肿瘤囊膜
And there is the tumor capsule.
里奇·帕克  有人知道吗
Richie Parker. Anyone?
那个赛车协会的吗  工程师  对吧
Isn't he a NASCAR guy? An engineer, right?
天生缺个胳膊
Born without arms?
奥坎波护士获得开门奖
And Nurse Ocampo gets the door prize.
现在我们从这个东西上面
And now we will take just a little piece
取一小块样品去做检查
of our friend here -- a nice sample to test.
谢谢  医生
Thank you, Doctor.
现在剩下的
And now the rest.
他或许没法自己系鞋带
He may not be able to tie his own shoes,
但我不会打赌他不能再比赛了
but I wouldn't bet against him ever competing again.
「不自由  毋宁死」
Aut libertatem aut mortem mihi da.
肖恩  你知道这是什么意思吗
Shaun, do you know that means?
不知道  跟手术无关
No. It's not relevant to this surgery.
有关系  查查看
Oh, it's relevant. Look it up.
无关
No, it's not.
心率和末二氧化碳浓度在上升
Heart rate and ETCO2 are rising.
体温稍有变化
Slight change in body temperature.
他的心率108了
His heart rate's 108.
检查插管  给他抽吸
Check tube placement and suction him.
他要是情况恶化  我们或许得放弃手术
If he takes a turn, we might have to abort.
我不觉得  都到这个地步了
I don't think so. I'm too far in.
稳住他
Keep him stable.
心动过速  心率攀升
He's tachy. Heart rate's climbing.
115  117  120  还在升
115, 117, 120, and rising.
他要室性心动过速了
He is going into v-tach.
罗伯特·奥托要死了
Robert Ato is dying.
我要慢慢把脑桥拿出来
I'm gonna pull out of the pons slowly.
等一下  你现在拿出来
Well, hold on. You pull out now,
可能会损坏到小脑脚
you might damage the cerebellar peduncle.
如果我现在不拿出来  他一旦开始抽搐就会死
If I don't get out now, I'll kill him if he starts seizing.
有点不对劲  心搏过速
Something's not right. Tachycardia?
心搏缓慢更说得通
Bradycardia would make more sense.
-有什么想法吗  -谁有想法
- Ideas. - Anyone?
告诉我你看到的
Tell me what you see.
心搏过速  体温再次升高
Tachycardia, rising body temperature again,
肌肉僵硬  二氧化碳在升高
muscle rigidity, CO2 is rising.
肌肉僵硬  哪一边
Muscle rigidity? Which side?
所有的肌肉
It's all over.
那就不是脑干的问题
Then it's not the brain stem.
否则只会有一边肌肉僵硬
We'd only have muscle rigidity on one side.
快想  心搏过速  体温升高  二氧化碳
Think. Tachycardia, rising temp, CO2...
二氧化碳...
CO2...
是麻药
It's the anesthesia.
恶性高热  把恶性高热急救车推过来
Malignant hyperthermia. Get the MH cart.
140毫克丹曲洛林  快
140 dantrolene, STAT.
卡卢  莫菲  多拿些降温毯过来
Kalu, Murphy, get as many cooling blankets as you can.
我们得把体温降下来
We need to get this temperature down.
-好了  -现在就去
- Coming out. - Now!
纯氧正压通气
Hyperventilate at 100% O2,
每分钟十升
10 liters per minute.
把麻醉剂都冲出来  降低末二氧化碳浓度
Flush out the old anesthetic, lower the ETCO2.
准备好万可松  注意他的情况
I want vecuronium on deck. We got to keep him under.
动起来
Let's move!
好了
And we're on.
体温降下来了
Uh, temp's not coming down.
等等
Wait.
二氧化碳降下来了
CO2 is coming down.
心率也降下来了
Heart rate is coming down, too.
体温38.3度
Temperature is 101.
好了  干得漂亮  各位
Okay. Nice work, everyone.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
泰瑞·福克斯
Terry Fox.
要不就是我个人的最爱  吉姆·阿伯特
Or my personal favorite -- Jim Abbott.
进来
Come in.
我想和你谈谈科利医生的事
I need to talk to you about Dr. Coyle.
布朗医生
Dr. Browne.
我也想和你说同样的事情
I wanted to talk to you about the same thing.
请吧
Please.
手术很成功
The surgery was a success.
结果比预想的要好
And the outcome might be better than expected.
你左边还是会有明显的神经功能障碍
There will still be significant neurological dysfunction
但是没我们预想得那么严重
on your left side, but not as much as we'd anticipated.
酷毙了
Sick!
谢谢
Thank you.
你做得很好  朋友
You did good, my friend.
你得耐心点
You have to be patient.
不要
Nah.
有耐心是一件坏事吗
Is patience a bad thing?
接受才是一件坏事
Acceptance is a bad thing.
我小时候不擅长玩抛接子游戏
When I was a kid, I -- I wasn't good at jack.
但我从没放弃
But I never quit.
我...
I...
成功了
found my thing.
永远都不要让别人告诉你
Don't ever let anyone tell you
你能做什么  不能...
what you can and can't...
做什么...
do.
昨晚的事对不起
I'm sorry. For last night.
昨天过得很不顺  我很累
It was a rough day. I was tired.
也许有点太...
Probably had a few too...
你和你爸的关系是你的事...
Your relationship with your father is your business --
尼尔  你不用这样
Neil, you don't have to.
我会给你爸打电话
I'll call your dad, and --
我不想要孩子
I don't want to have kids.
肖恩  我送你回家
Shaun, I'm gonna drive you home.
你会见到梅利莎
You're gonna see Melissa.
如果你不喜欢她  她就会离开
If you don't like her, she'll leave.
但是不要再逃避了
But there's no more running away.
你觉得我为什么要这么做
Why do you think I'm doing this?
因为你很固执
Because you are stubborn.
好吧  是的  好  你说得对  我很固执
Ok-Okay, yeah, okay, sure. I'm stubborn.
但是我这都是为了你  好吗
But I'm doing this for you, okay?
这样你就可以过上更好的生活
So that you can have a better life,
过上更开心的生活
so that you can have a happier life.
如果这不会让我开心呢
What if it doesn't make me happy?
如果这只让你感到开心呢
What if it only makes you happy?
你觉得我这么做是为了让自己开心
You think -- You think I'm doing this to make me happy?
我不开心  肖恩
I'm not happy, Shaun.
我一点也不开心  你知道吗
I'm not close to being happy, and you know what?
我不想再解释了
I am done explaining,
我不想再讨好你  我不想再说了
I am done bribing, and I am done talking.
-现在快走吧  -不  不不  不
- Now let's go. - No. N-No. No!
-走  -不
- Let's go! - No!
不
No.
不  我  我想自己做决定
No, I -- I want to make my own decisions.
-我...  -肖恩  你能小点声吗  拜托
- I -- - Shaun, can you keep your voice down, please? Please?
你不能一直这么命令我
You -- You cannot keep ordering me around, okay?
你不是我爸
You're not my father!
我知道
I know that.
肖恩  我不明白
Shaun, I don't understand...
好  你不想...为什么这让你如此苦恼
Okay.You don't let ...why this is so upsetting.
-有人告诉过你该怎么做  -我不明白
- Anyone ever tell you what you can and can't do-- - I don't get it.
肖恩  冷静点  拜托
Shaun, let's just calm down now, please.
-好了  好了  -永远都不要让别人告诉你
- Okay, okay. - Don't let anyone
你能做什么  不能做什么
ever tell you what you can and can't do!
冷静点  肖恩  别这样
Hey, just calm -- Shaun. Hey,
-我想自己做决定  -肖恩
- I want to make my own decisions. - Shaun.
-我想自己做决定  -好  好  好
- I want to make my own decisions! - Okay, okay, okay.
-我只是想帮忙  -我想自己做...
- I'm just trying to help. - I want make my own --
-我不需要帮忙  -肖恩
- I don't want help! - Shaun!
我...
I --
你在想什么
What were you thinking?!
我不需要你为我打架
I do not need you to fight my battles,
我也没有要求你这样做过
and I certainly never asked you to.
如果你真的尊重我的话
And if you really respected me,
你就不会像对待一个
you would not treat me like some damsel
需要保护的小姑娘似的对待我
who needed protection, okay?
你会给予我
You would treat me with the respect
应有的尊重
that you would automatically give to a man.
你会像对待有自理能力的人一样对待我
You'd treat me like a person capable of handling her own life!
也许  也许这对你要求太多了
And maybe -- maybe it's too much to ask of you.
很显然安德鲁斯同意你的看法
Apparently Andrews agrees with you.
我因为殴打同事被解雇了
I've just been fired for physically assaulting an employee.
肖恩  肖恩
Shaun? Shaun!
他去哪了
Where would he go?
有他想去的地方吗
Is there a place he likes to hang out,
他觉得舒服的地方
a place where he feels comfortable?
不  我不知道
No, I don't know.
他不在医院
I mean, he's not at the hospital.
以前这里有一张肖恩和...
And there used to be a picture here of Shaun...
他弟弟史蒂夫的照片
and his brother, Steve.
你觉得这是什么意思
What do you think that means?
意思是他不会回来了
It means he's not coming back.